This is a text file!

------ different python versions, management and creation ------

python -m pip install --upgrade pip==<version>   

python3.11 -m venv myenv   
source myenv/bin/activate  # On Windows: myenv\\Scripts\\activate   
For easier management of multiple Python versions, use pyenv

Install and switch between multiple Python versions globally or per project.
Create virtual environments with specific versions using pyenv virtualenv 3.11.4 myproject.

This creates a .python-version file in your project directory, automatically using that version when you enter the folder.